

Experience

Lead ux designer at 99x - working for Unimicro AS, Norway

Fintech and accounting - Feb 2023 - Today (1 year 1 month)

- Led project, designing the invoice payment experience for mobile application and redesign the time module for mobile application to maximise user engagement with the app and strengthen the CSAT score of the mobile application.
- Guided in implementing the Unimicro design system by collaborating with the designers and developers which maximises the team productivity with effortless collaboration. Plus facilitated in increasing the brand harmony among Unimicro products.
- Conducted a comprehensive accessibility audit for unimicro mobile app. Worked together with mobile developers to implement the accessibility features, which made the overall app more accessible for users.

Senior ux designer at 99x - working for Unimicro AS, Norway

Fintech and accounting - Jun 2021 - Feb 2023 (1 year 5 months)

- Worked together with the UX team from Unimicro, as well as stakeholders of partner banks, on web application usability improvements.
- Led the mobile app UX design by working closely with a multidisciplinary agile team consisting product owners, UX designers, developers and testers.
- Responsible for maintaining the both mobile application and web application Figma component library.

UI/ UX engineer at Epic Lanka

Fintech and banking - Aug 2017 - Jun 2021 (3 years 10 months)

- Worked as a UX designer for over 8 fintech projects. Collaborated closely with multidisciplinary project teams and engage with stakeholders from prominent banks in Sri Lanka.
- Led multiple projects as the main UI designer.
- I played a pivotal role in projects NDB NEOS banking solution, FriMi, BOC Smart Pay, NTB mobile banking and Epic Premier Plus.
- Contributed to UI implementation projects using Angular, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SASS, and SCSS frontend technologies.
- Won NBQSA National ICT Awards Best Mobile Payment Application of the Year in 2019 (BOC Smart Pay).
- Awarded as the best performer in the Epic Lanka UX team for the year 2020-2021.

Education

University of Colombo

Bachelor of Science - 2014 - 2018

 Majored in business information systems (marketing, product development, economics, HCI, Web development)

Portfolio

hashannilupull.com

About

6+ years of experience in UX design, Accessibility and design systems. Hands on experience in fintech domain products and enterprise level application design. With a keen interest in accessibility and design systems.

Skills

- UX Research
- UI/ Interaction design
- Data analysis
- Prototyping
- Usability testing
- Accessibility testing
- Design systems
- Data visualization

Tools

- Figma/ XD
- Adobe CC softwares
- HTML & CSS
- Prototyping
- JavaScript
- JIRA

Interesting facts

- I have conducted educational sessions for major universities in Sri Lanka.
- I like to play badminton and go on hiking.
- I have 2 weird hobbies, collecting sneakers and building keyboards.

Contacts

hashan.nilupul@live.com +94 712 622 470

Reference available on request.